<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>FRB: Finance and Economics Discussion Series Working Papers</title>
        <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/feeds.htm]]></link>
        <description><![CDATA[Staff working papers in the Finance and Economics Discussion Series (FEDS) are preliminary materials circulated to stimulate discussion and critical comment. The analysis and conclusions set forth are those of the authors and do not indicate concurrence by other members of the research staff or the Board of Governors. References in publications to the Finance and Economics Discussion Series (other than acknowledgment) should be cleared with the author(s) to protect the tentative character of these papers.]]></description>
        <language>en</language>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Non-monetary news in Fed announcements: Evidence from the corporate bond market(Revised)</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/monetary-policy-and-the-corporate-bond-market-how-important-is-the-fed-information-effect.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/monetary-policy-and-the-corporate-bond-market-how-important-is-the-fed-information-effect.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/michael-smolyansky.htm">Michael Smolyansky</a> and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/gustavo-a-suarez.htm">Gustavo Suarez</a><br><br>When the Federal Reserve tightens monetary policy, do the prices of riskier assets fall relative to safer assets? Or, do investors interpret policy tightening as a signal that economic fundamentals are stronger than they previously believed, thus leading riskier assets to outperform? We present evidence that the latter of these two forces empirically dominates within the U.S. corporate bond market. Following an unanticipated monetary policy tightening, riskier corporate bonds outperform safer corporate bonds, demonstrating the importance of an informational, or nonmonetary, component within monetary policy announcements.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:34:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Beliefs, Aggregate Risk, and the U.S. Housing Boom(Revised)</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/beliefs-aggregate-risk-and-the-u-s-housing-boom.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/beliefs-aggregate-risk-and-the-u-s-housing-boom.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/margaret-m-jacobson.htm">Margaret M. Jacobson</a><br><br>Endogenously optimistic beliefs about future house prices can account for the increase, time-path, and volatility of house prices in the U.S. housing boom of the 2000s without shocks to housing preferences. In a general equilibrium model with incomplete markets and aggregate risk, heterogeneous agents endogenously form beliefs about future house prices in response to shocks to fundamentals. When fundamentals like credit conditions loosen, agents can only partially revise up their beliefs, resulting in increasingly optimistic beliefs that are consistent with both novel and existing empirical evidence. Because endogenous beliefs are sensitive to policy interventions, how beliefs are formed in housing booms has direct implications for prudential policy.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:02:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: A Stock Return Decomposition Using Observables(Revised)</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/a-stock-return-decomposition-using-observables.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/a-stock-return-decomposition-using-observables.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/benjamin-knox.htm">Benjamin Knox</a> and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/annette-vissing-jorgensen.htm">Annette Vissing-Jorgensen</a><br><br>We propose a new method for decomposing realized stock market capital gains into contributions from changes to the real yield curve, equity premia, and expected dividends. The method centers on changes to observable inputs of the present value formula and requires no regressions or log-linearization. In S&amp;P500 data for 2005-2023, changes to expected dividends dominated the cumulative capital gain. Changes to the real yield curve and equity premia contributed more to capital gain fluctuations. A mix of higher equity premia and lower expected earnings drove the 2008 and 2020 market declines, while higher real yields drove the 2022 market drop.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:55:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Decoding Equity Market Reactions to Macroeconomic News</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/decoding-equity-market-reactions-to-macroeconomic-news.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/decoding-equity-market-reactions-to-macroeconomic-news.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/michele-modugno.htm">Michele Modugno</a> and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/dino-palazzo.htm">Dino Palazzo</a><br><br>The equity market&#8217;s reaction to macroeconomic news is consistent with the propagation of news into the real economy. We embody all the macro news in an activity news index and a price news index that together explain 34% of the quarterly stock price returns variation. When those indexes capture a stream of favorable macroeconomic surprises, publicly traded firms experience increases in revenues, profitability, financing, and investment activities. The firm-level results lead up to an expansion of the real side of the whole U.S. economy. Our findings, taken together, show that stock prices&#8217; reactions to macro news have a strong association with firm-level and economy-wide growth.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:10:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Spatially Mapping Banks' Commercial &amp; Industrial Loan Exposures: Including an Application to Climate-Related Risks</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/spatially-mapping-banks-commercial-industrial-loan-exposures.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/spatially-mapping-banks-commercial-industrial-loan-exposures.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/benjamin-dennis.htm">Benjamin N. Dennis</a>, Gurubala Kotta, and Caroline Conley Norris<br><br>The correlation of the spatial distribution of banking exposures with changes in spatial patterns of economic activity (e.g., internal migration, changes in agglomeration patterns, climate change, etc.) may have financial stability implications. We therefore study the spatial distribution of large U.S. banks&#39; commercial and industrial (C&amp;I) lending portfolios. We construct a novel dataset that augments FR Y-14Q regulatory data with borrower microdata for a more granular understanding of where banks&#39; exposures are located by looking beyond headquarters to the location of facilities. We find that banks are exposed to almost all U.S. counties, with clustered exposure in certain geographies. We then use our dataset for a climate-related application by analyzing what fraction of C&amp;I loans have been extended to firms that operate in areas vulnerable to physical risks, identifying, for example, counties where both (i) banks are highly exposed via their lending portfolios, and (ii) physical risks have historically resulted in large losses. Results of this kind can help inform risk management and be used to improve resilience to future stresses.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:31:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Impact of the Volcker Rule on the Trading Revenue of Largest U.S. Trading Firms During the COVID-19 Crisis Period</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/impact-of-the-volcker-rule-on-the-trading-revenue-of-largest-us-trading-firms-during-the-covid-19-crisis-period.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/impact-of-the-volcker-rule-on-the-trading-revenue-of-largest-us-trading-firms-during-the-covid-19-crisis-period.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/zach-modig.htm">Zach Modig</a>, <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/hulusi-inanoglu.htm">Hulusi Inanoglu</a>, and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/david-k-lynch.htm">David Lynch</a><br><br>Using a novel data collection, we examine the impact of the Volcker Rule on trading revenue of the 21 largest U.S. trading firms during the 100 day stress period centered on the COVID-19 financial crisis. We find that despite the market volatility, trading profits were consistent with volume-driven fees, commissions, and widening of the bid-ask spread. This work adds to the growing body of evidence that a consequence of the Volcker Rule on firm revenue associated with trading is increased financial stability and decreased risk exposure to market shocks.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:30:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Nonparametric Time Varying IV-SVARs: Estimation and Inference</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/nonparametric-time-varying-iv-svars-estimation-and-inference.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/nonparametric-time-varying-iv-svars-estimation-and-inference.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/robin-braun.htm">Robin Braun</a>, George Kapetanios, Massimiliano Marcellino<br><br>This paper studies the estimation and inference of time-varying impulse response functions in structural vector autoregressions (SVARs) identified with external instruments. Building on kernel estimators that allow for nonparametric time variation, we derive the asymptotic distributions of the relevant quantities. Our estimators are simple and computationally trivial and allow for potentially weak instruments. Simulations suggest satisfactory empirical coverage even in relatively small samples as long as the underlying parameter instabilities are sufficiently smooth. We illustrate the methods by studying the time-varying effects of global oil supply news shocks on US industrial production.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 6 Jan 2025 18:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Predicting College Closures and Financial Distress</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/predicting-college-closures-and-financial-distress.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/predicting-college-closures-and-financial-distress.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Robert Kelchen, Dubravka Ritter, and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/douglas-a-webber.htm">Douglas Webber</a><br><br>In this paper, we assemble the most comprehensive dataset to date on the characteristics of colleges and universities, including dates of operation, institutional setting, student body, staff, and finance data from 2002 to 2023. We provide an extensive description of what is known and unknown about closed colleges compared with institutions that did not close. Using this data, we first develop a series of predictive models of financial distress, utilizing factors like operational revenue/expense patterns, sources of revenue, metrics of liquidity and leverage, enrollment/staff patterns, and prior signs of significant financial strain. We benchmark these models against existing federal government screening mechanisms such as financial responsibility scores and heightened cash monitoring. We document a high degree of missing data among colleges that eventually close and show that this is a key impediment to identifying at risk institutions. We then show that modern machine learning techniques, combined with richer data, are far more effective at predicting college closures than linear probability models, and considerably more effective than existing accountability metrics. Our preferred model, which combines an off-the-shelf machine learning algorithm with the richest set of explanatory variables, can significantly improve predictive accuracy even for institutions with complete data, but is particularly helpful for predicting instances of financial distress for institutions with spotty data. Finally, we conduct simulations using our estimates to contemplate likely increases in future closures, showing that enrollment challenges resulting from an impending demographic cliff are likely to significantly increase annual college closures for reasonable scenarios.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 6 Jan 2025 18:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: "Good" Inflation, "Bad" Inflation: Implications for Risky Asset Prices</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/good-inflation-bad-inflation-implications-for-risky-asset-prices.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/good-inflation-bad-inflation-implications-for-risky-asset-prices.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Diego Bonelli, <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/dino-palazzo.htm">Berardino Palazzo</a>, <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/ram-s-yamarthy.htm">Ram S. Yamarthy</a><br><br>Using inflation swap prices, we study how changes in expected inflation affect firm-level credit spreads and equity returns, and uncover evidence of a time-varying inflation sensitivity. In times of "good inflation," when inflation news is perceived by investors to be more positively correlated with real economic growth, movements in expected inflation substantially reduce corporate credit spreads and raise equity valuations. Meanwhile in times of "bad inflation," these effects are attenuated and the opposite can take place. These dynamics naturally arise in an equilibrium asset pricing model with a time-varying inflation-growth relationship and persistent macroeconomic expectations.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 6 Jan 2025 18:20:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Missing Data Substitution for Enhanced Robust Filtering and Forecasting in Linear State-Space Models</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/missing-data-substitution-for-enhanced-robust-filtering-and-forecasting-in-linear-state-space-models.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/missing-data-substitution-for-enhanced-robust-filtering-and-forecasting-in-linear-state-space-models.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/dobrislav-dobrev.htm">Dobrislav Dobrev</a> and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/pawel-j-szerszen.htm">Paweł J. Szerszeń</a><br><br>Replacing faulty measurements with missing values can suppress outlier-induced distortions in state-space inference. We therefore put forward two complementary methods for enhanced outlier-robust filtering and forecasting: supervised missing data substitution (MD) upon exceeding a Huber threshold, and unsupervised missing data substitution via exogenous randomization (RMDX).]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 3 Jan 2025 20:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Trend-Cycle Decomposition and Forecasting Using Bayesian Multivariate Unobserved Components</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/trend-cycle-decomposition-and-forecasting-using-bayesian-multivariate-unobserved-components.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/trend-cycle-decomposition-and-forecasting-using-bayesian-multivariate-unobserved-components.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/mohammad-r-jahan-parvar.htm">Mohammad R. Jahan-Parvar</a>, Charles Knipp, and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/pawel-j-szerszen.htm">Paweł J. Szerszeń</a><br><br>We propose a generalized multivariate unobserved components model to decompose macroeconomic data into trend and cyclical components. We then forecast the series using Bayesian methods. We document that a fully Bayesian estimation, that accounts for state and parameter uncertainty, consistently dominates out-of-sample forecasts produced by alternative multivariate and univariate models. In addition, allowing for stochastic volatility components in variables improves forecasts. To address data limitations, we exploit cross-sectional information, use the commonalities across variables, and account for both parameter and state uncertainty. Finally, we find that an optimally pooled univariate model outperforms individual univariate specifications, and performs generally closer to the benchmark model.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Measuring the Euro Area Output Gap</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/measuring-the-euro-area-output-gap.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/measuring-the-euro-area-output-gap.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Matteo Barigozzi, Claudio Lissona, and <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/matteo-luciani.htm">Matteo Luciani</a><br><br>We measure the Euro Area (EA) output gap and potential output using a non-stationary dynamic factor model estimated on a large dataset of macroeconomic and financial variables. From 2012 to 2023, we estimate that the EA economy was tighter than the European Commission and the International Monetary Fund estimate, suggesting that the slow EA growth is the result of a potential output issue, not a business cycle issue. Moreover, we find that credit indicators are crucial for pinning down the output gap, as excluding them leads to estimating a lower output gap in periods of debt build-up and a higher gap in periods of deleveraging.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:04:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Hidden Risk</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/hidden-risk.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/hidden-risk.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/daniel-j-barth.htm">Daniel Barth</a>, <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/phillip-monin.htm">Phillip J. Monin</a>, Emil Siriwardane, and Adi Sunderam<br><br>Since 2013, large U.S. hedge fund advisers have been required to report risk exposures in their regulatory filings. Using these data, we first establish that managers&#8217; perceptions of risk contain useful information that is not embedded in fund returns. Investor flows do not respond to this information when managers perceive higher risk than what their past returns would indicate, suggesting managers strategically communicate their risk assessments with investors. During market downturns, investors withdraw capital from funds whose managers perceive higher risk, suggesting they find the performance of these funds in adverse market conditions surprising. These funds are identifiable ex-ante with information that is available to investors.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:03:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: Life-Cycle Portfolio Choices and Heterogeneous Stock Market Expectations</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/life-cycle-portfolio-choices-and-heterogeneous-stock-market-expectations.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/life-cycle-portfolio-choices-and-heterogeneous-stock-market-expectations.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Mateo Vel&aacute;squez-Giraldo<br><br>Survey measurements of households&#39; expectations about U.S. equity returns show substantial heterogeneity and large departures from the historical distribution of actual returns. The average household perceives a lower probability of positive returns and a greater probability of extreme returns than history has exhibited. I build a life-cycle model of saving and portfolio choices that incorporates beliefs estimated to match these survey measurements of expectations. This modification enables the model to greatly reduce a tension in the literature in which models that have aimed to match risky portfolio investment choices by age have required much higher estimates of the coefficient of relative risk aversion than models that have aimed to match age profiles of wealth. The tension is reduced because beliefs that are more pessimistic than the historical experience reduce people&#39;s willingness to invest in stocks.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:02:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>FEDS Paper: A Market Interpretation of Treatment Effects</title>
            <link><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/a-market-interpretation-of-treatment-effects.htm]]></link>
            <guid><![CDATA[https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/a-market-interpretation-of-treatment-effects.htm]]></guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/robert-j-minton.htm">Robert Minton</a> and Casey B. Mulligan<br><br>Markets, likened to an invisible hand, often appear to contradict econometric assumptions that rule out spillovers of one person&#8217;s treatment on another&#8217;s outcomes. This paper provides a simple statistical framework highlighting that controls are indirectly affected by the treatment through the market. Further, the effect of the treatment on the treated reveals only part of the consequence for the treated of treating the entire market. When combined with economic theory, our framework leads to a new application of Marshall&#8217;s Laws of Derived Demand that relates econometric estimates of treatment effects in the marketplace to the substitution and scale effects of demand theory. We show how treatment-effect estimators can diverge &#8211; both in magnitude and direction &#8211; from the causal effects of treatment on the treated or counterfactual policies treating all market participants. The framework shows how the consequences of targeted treatments reveal the effects of marketwide treatments, and the role of market frictions in that inference. Examples from labor, public finance, economic geography, development, and the macro literature on the &#8220;missing intercept&#8221; are provided.]]></description>
            <category>FEDS Paper</category>
            <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:01:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>