<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/search?p_p_id=estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet&amp;p_p_lifecycle=2&amp;p_p_state=maximized&amp;p_p_mode=view&amp;p_p_resource_id=atom&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_theme=PER_INDCOM&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_collection=CAT_PREREL" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <title>Eurostat - Custom RSS Feed</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat" />
  <link rel="next" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/search?p_p_id=estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet&amp;p_p_lifecycle=2&amp;p_p_state=maximized&amp;p_p_mode=view&amp;p_p_resource_id=atom&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_theme=PER_INDCOM&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_collection=CAT_PREREL&amp;pageNumber=2" />
  <link rel="last" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/search?p_p_id=estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet&amp;p_p_lifecycle=2&amp;p_p_state=maximized&amp;p_p_mode=view&amp;p_p_resource_id=atom&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_theme=PER_INDCOM&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_collection=CAT_PREREL&amp;pageNumber=116" />
  <link rel="related" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/rss/about-rss" />
  <subtitle>This feed has been created based on your search query. For more information, please consult the related help page.</subtitle>
  <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/en/search?p_p_id=estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet&amp;p_p_lifecycle=2&amp;p_p_state=maximized&amp;p_p_mode=view&amp;p_p_resource_id=atom&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_theme=PER_INDCOM&amp;_estatsearchportlet_WAR_estatsearchportlet_collection=CAT_PREREL</id>
  <updated>2025-01-20T10:00:00Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Production in construction up by 1.2% in the euro area and by 1.3% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-20012025-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-20012025-ap</id>
    <updated>2025-01-20T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-20T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In November 2024, compared with October 2024, seasonally adjusted production in construction increased by 1.2% in the euro area and by 1.3% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In October 2024, production in construction grew by 0.8% in...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Industrial production up by 0.2% in the euro area and by 0.1% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-15012025-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-15012025-ap</id>
    <updated>2025-01-15T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-15T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In November 2024, compared with October 2024, seasonally adjusted industrial production increased by 0.2% in the euro area and by 0.1% the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In October 2024, industrial production grew by 0.2% in the euro are...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Services production up by 0.3% in the euro area and by 0.5% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-10012025-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-10012025-ap</id>
    <updated>2025-01-10T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-10T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In October 2024, compared with September 2024, seasonally adjusted services production increased by 0.3% in the euro area and by 0.5% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In September 2024, services production fell by 0.1% in the euro a...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Volume of retail trade up by 0.1% in the euro area and by 0.2% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-09012025-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-09012025-ap</id>
    <updated>2025-01-09T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-09T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In November 2024, compared with October 2024, the seasonally adjusted retail trade volume increased by 0.1% in the euro area and by 0.2% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In October 2024, retail trade volume fell by 0.3% in the euro ...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Industrial producer prices up by 1.6% in the euro area and by 1.7% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-08012025-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-08012025-ap</id>
    <updated>2025-01-08T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-08T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In November 2024, compared with October 2024, industrial producer prices increased by 1.6% in the euro area and by 1.7% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In October 2024, industrial producer prices grew by 0.4% in both the euro area ...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Production in construction up by 1.0% in the euro area and by 0.7% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-18122024-bp" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-18122024-bp</id>
    <updated>2024-12-18T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-18T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In October 2024, compared with September 2024, seasonally adjusted production in construction increased by 1.0% in the euro area and by 0.7% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In September 2024, production in construction fell by 0.3%...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Industrial production stable in the euro area and up by 0.3% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-13122024-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-13122024-ap</id>
    <updated>2024-12-13T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In October 2024, compared with September 2024, seasonally adjusted industrial production remained stable in the euro area and increased by 0.3% the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In September 2024, industrial production fell by 1.5% in t...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Services production down by 0.5% in the euro area and by 0.2% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-06122024-bp" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-06122024-bp</id>
    <updated>2024-12-06T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-06T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In September 2024, compared with August 2024, seasonally adjusted services production decreased by 0.5% in the euro area and by 0.2% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In August 2024, services production grew by 0.5% in both the euro ...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Volume of retail trade down by 0.5% in the euro area and by 0.3% in the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-05122024-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-05122024-ap</id>
    <updated>2024-12-05T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-05T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In October 2024, compared with September 2024, the seasonally adjusted retail trade volume decreased by 0.5% in the euro area and by 0.3% in the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In September 2024, retail trade volume grew by 0.5% in the eu...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Industrial producer prices up by 0.4% in both the euro area and the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-04122024-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-04122024-ap</id>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In October 2024, compared with September 2024, industrial producer prices increased by 0.4% in both the euro area and the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In September 2024, industrial producer prices fell by 0.6% in both the euro area and...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Production in construction down by 0.1% in both the euro area and the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-20112024-ap" />
    <author>
      <name>Eurostat</name>
      <uri>http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/product?code=4-20112024-ap</id>
    <updated>2024-11-20T10:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2024-11-20T10:00:00Z</published>
    <summary type="html">In September 2024, compared with August 2024, seasonally adjusted production in construction decreased by 0.1% in both the euro area and the EU, according to first estimates from Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Union. In August 2024, production in construction remained stable in the...</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
